# 大爷又学了一个炸油饼
This time, Da Ye learnt youbing (deep-fried cakes)
# 我专门找了一个老师傅学的
I found a master chef to learn it
# 在北京做油饼特别棒的一师傅
A chef that's especially good at making youbing
# 一斤面  还是标准粉吗 标准粉
- 1 jin of flour (500g). All purpose flour, like before?
- All purpose flour
# 油条油饼 最好是标准粉
It's best to use all purpose flour for youtiao (deep-fried dough strips) and youbing
# 八克盐 一斤面
8 grams of salt. 1 jin of flour
# 这是三克 六克 八克
3 grams, 6 grams, 8 grams
# 这是泡打粉
Baking powder
# 四克 这稍微多一点不要紧
4 grams. We can use a bit more. Doesn't matter
# 五克 四五克
5 grams, or around
# 还有什么 小苏打
What else? Baking soda
# 小苏打这作用挺多的
Baking soda is quite useful
# 让它起是吧 起脆 一小勺
- For rising?
- Rising and crispness. A small spoonful
# 这两样搁好了以后
With these two in
# 我们先给它拌均
Let's first mix it evenly
# 要不然你和的时候就和不均
Otherwise you can't knead the dough evenly
# 搁一个鸡蛋就行了
One egg is enough
# 打了 蛋清蛋黄全用
Crack it. Both yolk and white
# 这水是二百七十克
We have 270g of water
# 但是得算上这鸡蛋
# 译注：没看懂这 270g 是包含鸡蛋还是不包含鸡蛋。含糊处理了
But we need to count the egg
# 打散以后我们把水兑进来
Beat it up, and water in
# 倒到鸡蛋里边 让它搅和均匀
- Pour the water into the egg
- And mix it well
# 我看倒了一半
You only poured half of it
# 有时候这面也有问题
Sometimes, there are issues with the flour
# 有的这面它干 它吃水
Some flour is dry. It aborbs a lot of water
# 把面给它均匀的打成啰嗦
First we knead the flour evenly into strips
# 再补点水
Some more water
# 我怎么记得那时候说和面
I remember we have a saying about kneading a dough
# 要手光 盆光 面光
We need "smooth hands, smooth bowl, smooth dough"
# 面它是光滑的 你说的是三光
- The dough should be smooth
- You are talking about "the three smooths"
# 这个面软的程度
The softness of the dough
# 基本上比烙饼的面 比较相似
It's similar to the dough for laobing (pan-seared cakes/pies)
# 就跟你上次做肉饼似的
译注：这里指的是往期视频大爷肉饼 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=085dZmraG4M
Like the meat pie you made last time
# 但是比那个要硬一点 得拿得起来
- But it's tougher than that
- So that you can grab it up
# 这个软硬程度差不多了是吧
The softness should be alright
# 已经好了
Alright now
# 我们在和的时候 可能要会黏手
When kneading, it may stick to you hands
# 这时候怎么办
- In this case
- What should we do?
# 加点油 十克 花生油吗
- Add some oil. 10 grams
- Peanut oil?
# 什么油都可以啊
Whatever oil will do
# 这面和好了以后要饧一饧
After keanding, we need to rest the dough
# 饧个十来分钟 再揉一揉
Rest it for about 10 minutes. Then knead it again
# 然后我们就给它放到冰箱里了
Then we refrigerate it
# 一般的明天早晨吃油饼 今天晚上（和）
Generally, if we want it for tomorrow morning, (knead it) this evening
# 如果要是晚上吃
If we want it for this evening
# 吃完中午饭就可以和上了
We can knead it after lunch
# 要多给它饧一饧
Gotta rest it well
# 一般的什么烙饼面 饺子面 面条面
Generally, for laobing, dumpings and noodles
# 刚开始和的时候效果都不是很好
When we first knead it, the dough doesn't look good
# 一会十分钟以后
After 10 minutes
# 咱们再把它和一下 就好了
We knead it again, it will be good
# 这面可饧半天了 咱看看怎么样啊
We've rested for quite a while. Let's check it out
# 再揉揉
Knead it more
# 你看这个越揉面纹越细
Look, the more we knead, the smoother it is
# 你看这个软硬也润了 光滑的
- Look at the softness, and the moisture
- So smooth
# 这要饧得饧个三四个小时
We need to rest it for 3 to 4 hours
# 因为它这里头有小苏打
Because it contains baking soda
# 得让它起作用
We need to make it effective
# 包的时候给它按一按
Press it when wrapping it up
# 夏天就得放冰箱里头
In summers, refrigerate it
# 冬天也得放冰箱里头
In winers, also refrigerate it
# 饧三四个小时就行
Just rest it for 3 to 4 hours
# 收起来了啊 好嘞 收起来吧
- Put in it
- All right! Put it in
# 等三个小时以后 炸一个看看效果
Three hours later, we'll fry one and see how it goes
# 三个小时多一点也没事 没问题
- Should be fine if it's more than three hours?
- No problems
# 吃不完两天都行
Even two days if you can't finish it up
# 油饼的面已经饧好了
The youbing dough is rested well
# 这案板上得放油 不然就粘上了
- We need some oil on the board
- Or it sticks
# 还得饧一饧
Need more resting
# 然后先把油烧上
Then we heat up the oil first
# 这个不需要热锅啊  这就是倒油就行了
- We don't need to warm up the wok?
- Just pour in the oil
# 大妈给点一下火
Please light it up, Da Ma
# 家里炸油饼别炸太大 用油用的太多
For home cooking, don't make the youbing too big, or it needs too much oil
# 家里炸呢炸的稍微小一点
For home cooking, we make it smaller
# 这先用不着了
We don't need it for now
# 这个给它拉一拉 软硬合适
Pull it. See, just the right softness
# 一拉它就长了 切成小剂儿
Easy to pull it longer. Cut it into strips
# 大小咱们自己自定  自己拿主意
- We decide the sizes by ourselves
- Make our own decisions
# 我为了让网友看这油饼
To show youbing to our audience
# 我专门找了一个老师傅在北京
I specifically found a master chef in Beijing
# 京城做油饼特别棒的一个师傅 跟他学的
An especially good youbing chef in Beijing. I learnt it from him
# 这个先搁一边
Put it away for now
# 北京人基本上都是这个习惯
Basically all Beijingers love it
# 豆浆油饼 豆浆油条 绝配
- Soy milk with youbing, or soy milk with youtiao
- The perfect combination
# 这面 特别软
The dough is super soft
# 给这个油饼稍微擀一擀
Roll the youbing for a bit
# 剌两个小口
And make two slices
# 人家专业拉口
This is the professional slicing
# 人家在外边邦邦一敲 敲俩眼儿
Those people outside knock it. "Bang, bang", two holes
# 那到底谁是专业
So who's the professional one then?
# 油饼就得剌口
Youbing has to be sliced
# 油饼的油温要高一些 七成热
Youbing needs hotter hoil. About 200 °C
# 有时候我们炸的时候就越炸越热
# 译注：这句话没看懂。含糊处理了
Sometimes it gets hotter and hotter when frying
# 油温低了它不容易起
It doesn't rise if the oil temperate is low
# 油温应该差不多了
The oil temperate looks good
# 提溜过来 下锅
Grab it here. Into the wok
# （油温）还是稍微低一点
(Oil temperate) still a bit low
# 没事 第一个
No worries. It's the first one
# 起来了 就颜色白点儿
- It has risen
- The color is pretty white
# 一般的炸这个是老油好
Generally, it's better to fry it with reused oil
# 炸过两回三回的
Oil reused for a couple times
# 大妈稍微搭把手 我再来第二个
Give me a hand, Da Ma. Let me make the second one
# 这个就好了
This one is done?
# 再来一个
The second one
# 下一个就起来了 马上就起
- The second one has risen
- It rises immediately
# 行嘞
Done
# 瞧我  大厨做二厨帮忙
Look at me. The head chef cooks, and the no.2 chef helps
# 不是 大爷做大妈帮忙
Nope. Da Ye cooks and Da Ma helps
# 我还不配当二厨啊
So I'm not even the no.2 chef?
# 快换事儿了
Close
# 切
Pfff
# 咱多炸几个 好吃
- Let's fry some more
- It's tasty!
# 回头咱请网友过来吃啊
Next time we can ask some audience to have it here
# 你看这个起的多好 来一特写
- Look at how well it has risen
- Give it a closeup
# 给大爷扔一边儿去了
Da Ye is out of the camera
# 不录大爷了
We don't film Da Ye any more
# 成了 关火
Done. Fire off
# 不少吧 行嘞
- Quite a lot?
- Good
# 大妈上这儿给照一个
Let's film it here, Da Ma
# 挨着我们老饭骨这个墩子
Next to our Lao Fan Gu chopping board
# 让大家看看 好看吧
- Show it to the crowd
- Looks good?
# 还真是挺好的 行不错
It's actually good. Alright, not bad!
# 大家试着做去
Everyone, please try it out
# 家有大厨
Having a chef at home...
# 你们幸福
You feel awesome
# 就是幸福
It is awesome!
# 全家幸福
The whole family feel awesome
# 我收摊儿了啊
I'm wrapping up